<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?>

<feed xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#" version="0.3" xml:lang="en-US">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/25652637" rel="service.post" title="On the FACE ....." type="application/atom+xml"/>
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/25652637" rel="service.feed" title="On the FACE ....." type="application/atom+xml"/>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">On the FACE .....</title>
<tagline mode="escaped" type="text/html">i will express here my heartfelt views.. right on the face, without thinking what anyone thinks abt them.. i dont give a damn...</tagline>
<link href="http://ontheface.blogspot.com" rel="alternate" title="On the FACE ....." type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-25652637</id>
<modified>2006-05-26T05:25:36Z</modified>
<generator url="http://www.blogger.com/" version="6.72">Blogger</generator>
<info mode="xml" type="text/html">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This is an Atom formatted XML site feed. It is intended to be viewed in a Newsreader or syndicated to another site. Please visit the <a href="http://help.blogger.com/bin/answer.py?answer=697">Blogger Help</a> for more info.</div>
</info>
<convertLineBreaks xmlns="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#">true</convertLineBreaks>
<entry xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/25652637/114862113690348506" rel="service.edit" title="In this age of &quot;democracy&quot;, the Govt.has muzzled the media?????" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>
<name>...PHOENIX...</name>
</author>
<issued>2006-05-25T22:22:00-07:00</issued>
<modified>2006-05-26T05:25:36Z</modified>
<created>2006-05-26T05:25:36Z</created>
<link href="http://ontheface.blogspot.com/2006/05/in-this-age-of-democracy-govthas.html" rel="alternate" title="In this age of &quot;democracy&quot;, the Govt.has muzzled the media?????" type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-25652637.post-114862113690348506</id>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">In this age of "democracy", the Govt.has muzzled the media?????</title>
<content mode="escaped" type="text/html" xml:base="http://ontheface.blogspot.com" xml:space="preserve">Hi friends.... this is a mail sent by an AIIMS student.. please read this.....&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also i m planning to start a blogathon on Anti reservations.. please leave ur blog addresses and names in comments so that i can write ur name here along with other participants.....&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dear friends please spend some time to read this. U can make a difference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As u all guys know that there have been lots of protests going on against the raise in reservations. All of us struggle for months and years to make our dreams come true; No body in the government is bothered about that. This new policy of govt ll be a major road block in the development of our nation and creation of a caste free society. I want to share some developments occurring here with respect to this issue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Abt 2 weeks back the Students Union ( SU ) of AIIMS ( UGs and Interns ) started the protests. they held peaceful march. Their main demand was to meet Honbl. Arjun Singh and to express their concern regarding the hike in reservations. What they got in return. Water canons, tear gas shells and Lathis. Some of the interns who were beaten were my friends and i could see their injury marks. Worse, some were girls. Sad isnt it ? Well next few days due to their constant struggle they could get to meet Dr Arjun Singh. No positive response was obtained. He however promised that before sending the bill to cabinet, he would inform the SU. The students continued to boycott their classes. Other medical colleges of delhi also joined. We Resident Doctors of AIIMS however were not actively participating. We wore black badges and attended few rallies.12 th May saw a new beginning. Our medical students were brutally assaulted by Delhi police. Injured were brought to AIIMS. Fracture hand bone, head injury, blunt trauma abdomen with intra-abdominal bleed; &gt; 300 students were manhandled including girls, stuffed in buses and taken to police station. I remember the dialogue from RDB.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This incident will prove to be a final nail in coffin for our Congress Govt. At around 3 pm the Resident Doctors Association ( RDA ) of AIIMS announced an indefinite strike. All Junior Residents ( Acad or Non-acad ) &amp; Senior Residents boycotted. Protest rally was organized that day.13 th may was the worst day in the history of our Indian Independence and so called Democracy. Medical Students of Mumbai were beaten like animals. Infact animals also are never treated like this. Every body would have witness the brutality of the Mumbai Police.17 - 18 year old medical students were beaten up. Future of our country treated like this? And these are the same Police Men who come to our OPD and ask for peferential treatment. Shame on them. And listen to what Bhujbal said on TV. I thought we need a real RDB now. This incident triggered the suppressed fire in each and every individual. We at AIIMS went on INDEFINITE HUNGER STRIKE from 14 th morning joined by medical students from MAMC Delhi, Lady Harding, RML Hosp, Rohtak Medical College .&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Slowly the fire spread to diferent states of our country. You know what happened in Blore. Calcutta, Orissa, Chattisgarh, Gujrat, Himachal Pradesh, Kerala boiled in protests. Students of Delhi University ( BSc BCom...) also joined the strikeThe hunger strike in AIIMS continues. More than 100 students and residents are sitting in the heat since 14 th morning just on plain water. Believe me we slept in the open last night empty stomach. Its only when rain started pouring we had go inside the audi and slept there.The IMA has announced comlete medical bandh today ( 15 th may ). Doctors from all over delhi have come to AIIMS and are holding protests. IITs and IIMs have joined the strike. Even patients and their attenders were of full support towards this cause.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One man said," My father is admitted in NS department and is fighting for his life and death, but i declare that i have no objection with ur strike. I support ur movement and the cause for which u re fighting. Our country needed this."All of us know what is right and what is wrong. Having said that i feel that each one of us should follow our conscience. I ve written this message because i felt there are many of who might not be aware of the exact situation. I request each one of u to please forward this to all ur friends, Medicos or Non-medicos.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every common man needs to be aware of the injustice and should be involved in this effort.This Movement will be a revolution in our independent country and will be the most significant event after the British Rule. It ll be the cause for the rewriting of Indian Constitution where just and meritorious people are not singled out and put to taste the adversities and someone else enjoys the benefit.The government cannot hide its inadequacies in providing equal opportunities to the under priviliged in rural areas by increasing the reservations. They have ruled the country for so many decades and if in this time they are not able to provide equalilty in primary and secondary education for in dian citizens they cannot mask their failure by providing reservations at each and every level. Its ridiculous. The whole issue of reservations was a political gimmic of the present govt to garner votes.Its time that things are not taken for granted by any one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Let it be a senior minister police or anyone else. Whole of our nation needs to get aware of the amount of hardwork and sacrifice we put to achieve our dreams. We should not allow anyone to make a mockery of our struggle in future.</content>
<draft xmlns="http://purl.org/atom-blog/ns#">false</draft>
</entry>
<entry xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#">
<link href="https://www.blogger.com/atom/25652637/114448967472062272" rel="service.edit" title="Why reservations in premier instis ???" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>
<name>...PHOENIX...</name>
</author>
<issued>2006-04-08T02:44:00-07:00</issued>
<modified>2006-04-08T09:47:54Z</modified>
<created>2006-04-08T09:47:54Z</created>
<link href="http://ontheface.blogspot.com/2006/04/why-reservations-in-premie_114448967472062272.html" rel="alternate" title="Why reservations in premier instis ???" type="text/html"/>
<id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-25652637.post-114448967472062272</id>
<title mode="escaped" type="text/html">Why reservations in premier instis ???</title>
<content type="application/xhtml+xml" xml:base="http://ontheface.blogspot.com" xml:space="preserve">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span style="font-weight: bold;font-size:78%;">To:  Indian Government</span> <p>
<span style="font-weight: bold;"> To:  Honourable President of India,</span>
<br/>
<br/>
<span style="font-weight: bold;">    Honourable Chief Justice of India,</span>
<br/>
<br/>
<span style="font-weight: bold;">    Honourable Prime Minister of India.</span>
<br/>
<br/>
<br/>
<br/>We are signing this petition to strongly detest the proposed reservation for OBC's in premier educational institutes.<br/>
<br/>We would like to call upon the office of Indian President/Prime Minister/ Chief Justice of India to act against the above declaration as:<br/>
<br/>
<br/>
<br/>1. Most of the reserved seats are filled by students belonging to families which have already benefitted from such a reservation earlier. This does not help the needy.<br/>
<br/>2. By reserving seats in institutes of higher education, government is shying away from it's responsibility of giving quality primary education to all and thereby providing a level playing field.<br/>
<br/>3. Short sighted politicians use reservations for their political gains and create divisions between the communities.<br/>
<br/>4. Many students belonging to the so called 'upper castes' are poor and are unable to get decent education while most reserved seats are filled by students who had got a decent education earlier.<br/>
<br/>5. Many students who fill the reserved seats drop out because they have not been selected based on their merit. This means a precious seat has been wasted in a premier college.<br/>
<br/>6. Admission to premier institutes is highly competitive and a large number of meritous students are left out because they have been born in a general category family.<br/>
<br/>7. With time prestige of these premier institutes would degrade as the students would not be admitted based on their merit but on their castes. This is already evident from the skewed placement statistics of the IIT's and IIM's.<br/>
<br/>
<br/>
<br/>We feel that there should be no reservations based solely on the principles of caste and government should instead focus on providing quality primary education to all. </p>
<p>  Sincerely,</p>
<p>Phoenix<br/>
</p>
<br/>
<p>
<br/>
</p>
<p>If u feel there is something in this post then sign this petition...</p>
<span style="font-size:130%;">
<span style="font-weight: bold;">http://www.petitiononline.com/obcrev/petition.html</span>
</span>
<a href="http://www.petitiononline.com/obcrev/petition.html">
<span style="font-size:130%;">
<span style="font-weight: bold;"/>
</span>
</a>
</div>
</content>
<draft xmlns="http://purl.org/atom-blog/ns#">false</draft>
</entry>
</feed>
